Jacky Shen (CST, CTC) / Sally Cai (CSP)
中文字幕由自组织Scrum团队提供 （Build 20180915）
yeah yeah. hi hi. hi, buddy
yeah yeah. hi hi. 你好伙计
you know you have to be on time for the daily standup
你知道你必须准时参加每日站会
it is the same time same location every day, loser!
每天都是同一时间、同一地点, 屌丝！
the daily stand-up is crucial,
每日站会是至关重要的
you can't be late for the daily stand-up
你每天都不能迟到
you don't let your teammates wait
你不能让你的队友等你
you know the first time I heard
当我第一次听说Scrum
about this SCRUM thing
I didn't think it would fit our organization, however
我不认为它适合我们的组织，但是
after we sent Ian to ScrumMaster training,
在我们派Ian去参加Scrum Master(CSM)培训之后,
things rapidly changed around here.
突然间周围迅速开始发生很多改变
I'm the process officer, wow
我是过程的督导，喔~
thanks Wendy
谢谢，温蒂
hi Mike, I can make this incredible deal
你好，麦克。 我将要搞一笔大买卖
lots of bonus, I just need a mount of change
会有大笔奖金, 只需要你改一点东西
it's just a few hours of work
只是几个小时的工作
Come on ! Can you do it for me?
来吧！你可以帮我做吗？
I will give you this donut if you do it.
我会送你这个甜甜圈的
You fool! Never interrupte the team!
傻瓜！永远不要打断团队的节奏！
They're in their sprints
他们在自己的Sprints(迭代短时间盒)里面工作
they have focus, so no changes! If you want extras,
他们要全神贯注，所以不要变更！ 如果你需要什么额外的东西，
go to the Product Owner.
去跟产品负责人(PO)商量
I am the process enabler, strong works great, but
我是这个过程的使能者，自己强力固然好，但
let the team do the work.
必须让团队自己决定怎么工作
that's what they're good at. they deserve being left alone
这也是他们最擅长的。他们应该独处
I'll take care of that.
我会确保这一点
Do I enjoy doing that? hell yeah!
我非常喜欢做这件事情吗? 当然咯！
after we introduce scrum, the productivity of our teams went
在我们引入Scrum以后，我们团队的生产力
through the roof, they focused on
冲破了天花板，他们专注在
maximizing value by delivering a new
商业价值的最大化上
version of our product every two weeks
每两周发布一个我们产品的新版本
rapid value creation is key.
关键就是要能够快速地产生价值。
Hey, I finished this feature yesterday
嘿，我昨天就已经把这个功能做完了
the code is done but we still need to run it
代码的确是写完了
to a regression test, quality is key
但我们还要跑回归测试，质量才是关键
I'm sure it works, I'll put it to done
我确信代码是可以运行的, 我要把它放在「完成」这边
it's not tested
它还没有被测试
Oh, done means done, if it's not done, it is not done
哦~ 完成就是完成,如果没有完成就是没有完成
Hey Lisa, you know that, don't mess up scrum board
你好 Lisa. 你知道的，不要搞乱了Scrum板
Ian is not only here to
Ian在这里不仅仅是
enable the process and protect the team
让过程运转起来，他还保护团队
he's also here to facilitate the team
他也会引导团队
and to coach them, he helps them to
扮演团队的教练, 他帮助团队
create the best day possible every day
尽量让他们的每一天都是最好的一天
Anyone like some coffee? yeah come on
你们想要点咖啡吗? 是的 来吧
Sit up straight, you don't want your back to get hurt
坐直了，别让你的背受伤。
Wait! let me help you with that
等等，我来帮你
Nice! there you must feel work much better now
舒服！现在感觉好点了吧
Enjoy your coffee.
好好享受咖啡吧
thanks Ian
谢谢，Ian
a scrum master needs to do what needs to be done
一个Scrum Master就应该做该做的事
I am a facilitator
作为一个引导师
it's not about me, it's about the team.
这不是关于我自己，而是团队。
anything that needs to be done, I take care of that
任何需要做的事情，我都会关心
hold on
等一下
hey Ian, speed up, we're losing power
嘿，Ian，快点儿，我们停电了
working on it
我正在努力
I'm back, yeah
我回来了
Ian is a scrum master
Ian是Scrum Master，
he protects the team he coaches the team
他保护团队，当团队的教练，
and he ensures that impediments are busted
并且他还保证移除障碍
and do I mind the way he does that? of course not!
我会介意他怎么做到的吗？当然不会!
it's the end result that counts
最终结果才是重要的
it's Scrum that makes it work
是Scrum令事情运作
it's the team that does the work
是团队在做实际的工作，但是
but still you do need your Scrum Master
你确实需要你的Scrum Master
Buy the book 《the power of Scrum》 at the Amazon.com
去优普丰敏捷学院 (www.UPerform.cn) 学学看看
now or else I will be there to
否则我将会
pay YOU a visit
来拜访你
Jacky Shen (CST, CTC) / Sally Cai (CSP)
中文字幕由自组织Scrum团队提供 （Build 20180915）